Guide to the Pittsburgh Academy of Medicine Records, 1878-1972 AIS.2017.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Scientific papers, 1917-1935; XIV.
  - Scientific papers, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Delirium Tremens", undated; 17.
    - "Erysipelas", undated; 18.
    - "Hyperthyroidism", March 8, 1917; 19.
    - Lead in Industry, February 27, 1917; 20.
    - "Non-Operative Treatment of Pelvic Inflammation", undated; 21.
    - "Some Aspects of the Ophthalmia Problem", undated; 22.
    - "Acquired Internal Hydrocephalus: Report of a Case Following Meningitis", February 13, 1917; 23.
    - "The Infected Gall Bladder", undated; 24.
  - Scientific papers, ca 1918 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Dr. C. C. Anderson, "Blood Pressure", undated; 1.
    - Dr. M. H. Baker, "Camp Observations on Pneumonia", undated; 2.
    - Dr. P. T. Billings, "Infectious Diarrhoea of Infancy", undated; 3.
    - Dr. L. C. Bixler, "A Case of Syphilitic Meningo-myelitis", undated; 4.
    - Dr. W. W. Blair, "Some Aspects of the Ophthalmia Problem", undated; 5.
    - Dr. S. A. Chalfant, "Non-operative Treatment of Pelvic Inflammation, undated; 6.
    - Dr. B. M. Dickinson, "Anaesthetic in a Tonsil Opertaion", undated; 7.
    - Dr. J. W. Dixon, "Empyema", undated; 8.
    - Dr. C. B. Edwards, "Spontaneous Hemorrages in the New Born", undated; 9.
    - Dr. C. J. Ellis, "A Case of Probable Obstruction of the Vas", undated; 10.
    - Dr. Ellis M. Frost, "Case Report of Morphinism Terminating in Ursemia", undated; 11.
    - Dr. C. C. Gaub, "The Infected Gall Bladder in its Relation to its Associated Glands", undated; 12.
    - Dr. J. A. Luchty, "The Failure of Gall Bladder Surgery as seen by the Internist", undated; 13.
    - Dr. E. E. Mayer, "The Sciaticas: The Endicular vs. the Neuritic Types", undated; 14.
    - Dr. W. C. Maxwell, "Ether Anaesthesia", undated; 15.
    - Dr. C. B. McAboy, "The Dietetic Management of Chronic Infectious Arthritis", undated; 16.
    - Dr. H. McReady, "Report of a Case of Retropharyngeal Abcess with Complications in an Infant, three month old", undated; 17.
    - Dr. T. E. McMurray, "Epilepsy with Case Histories", undated; 18.
    - Dr. Milligan, "Case of Actinomycosis with Mastioditis", undated; 19.
    - Dr. C. C. Sandels, "Acude Suppurative Otitis Media", undated; 20.
    - Dr. J. D. Singley, "The Indications for Either a Cholecystectomy or a Choleycystosomy at Operation", undated; 21.
    - Dr. Acheson Stewart, "Changes, Pathologic and Anatomic Occurring Following Cholecystectomy and Cholecystostomy", undated; 22.
    - Dr. C. A. Stillwagen, "The Operative Treatment of Pelvic Inflammation", undated; 23.
    - Dr. Paul Titus, "Obstetrical Superstitions", undated; 24.
    - Dr. J. M. Thorne, "A Case of Filariasis Treated with Salvarsan", undated; 25.
    - Dr. F. L. Todd, "Report of Two Cases of Meckel's Diverticulum", undated; 26.
    - Dr. J. E. Willetts, "Study of the White Corpuscles in Their Circulation Through the Cornea", undated; 27.
    - Dr. J. H. Whitcraft, "Some Observations on the Diagnosis and Treatment of Cerebro Spinal Lues", undated; 28.
    - Dr. Utley, "An unusual case of Lobar Pneumonia with Meningismus", undated; 29.
    - Dr. I. J. Moyer and Dr. J. I. Johnston, Case reports on pneumonia., undated; 30.
    - Dr. Theodore Baker, "Conservative Surgery of the Seminal Vesicles", undated; 31.
  - Scientific papers, 1920-1923 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Dr. James M. Long, A case of carcinoma of the breast, February 28, 1922; 1.
    - Dr. Charles B. Maits, "Banti's Disease", undated; 2.
    - Dr. F. W. Mathewson, "Report of the Progress of a Few Cases Following Tonsillectomy", March 7, 1922; 3.
    - Dr. C. B. McAboy, "Diarrhea in Old Age", undated; 4.
    - Dr. J. H. McCready, "Removal of Cat from Left Bronchus", undated; 5.
    - Dr. W. B. McKenna, "Post-Operative Parotitis", undated; 6.
    - J. E. [McMurray?], "Tincture of Iodine", undated; 7.
    - Dr. Nicholas Schillito, "Treatment of Gonnorhea in Women", undated; 8.
    - Dr. Chas. C. Stanton, Report on a case of throat swelling, February 28, 1922; 9.
    - Dr. J. N. Stanton and Louis Taft, "Contenital Total Hemihypertrophy", undated; 10.
    - Dr. Acheson Stewart, "Technic of Prostatectomy", February 28, 1922; 11.
    - Dr. Geo. Wright, Syphilis, undated; 12.
    - Dr. James O. Wallace, "Thomas Bannon", May 9, 1922; 13.
    - Dr. E. A. Weisser, "Tobacco Amblyopia", undated; 14.
    - Dr. Whitcraft, "Some Observations Upon Sore Throat", undated; 15.
    - Dr. Ernest W. Willetts, "Treatment of Syphilis with Inveolvement of Central Nervous System, Spinal Fluid Examinations", undated; 16.
    - Dr. Charles Edward Ziegler, "Consideration of Hydramnios with Especial Reference to the Etiology of the Condition", undated; 17.
    - Extopic pregnancy, undated; 18.
    - "Streptococcal Generalized Infection with report of two cases", undated; 19.
    - "The Bacteriologic Examination of Pus from Mastoid Operation with Complications from Various Organisms", undated; 20.
    - "Acute Perforating Duodenal and Gastric Ulcer with Report of Cases", undated; 21.
    - Surgical reform, undated; 22.
    - Case study: Mary M. (abdominal pain), undated; 23.
    - Case study: T. J. (car accident), 24.
    - "Functional Efficiency of Circulatory System with Special Reference to Pre-operative Risk", undated; 25.
    - "Some Suggestions for the Treatment of Hyperthyroidism", undated; 26.
    - "Lithiasis of the Upper Urinary Tract", November 1, 1921; 27.
    - "Modern Methods in the Dispensary", undated; 28.
    - "Tetany", undated; 29.
    - "Endocrine Disturbance in Mental Defectives", undated; 30.
    - "Vincent's Infection", undated; 31.
  - Scientific papers, 1920-1923 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Dr. J. I. Johnson, "Oseophageal Diverticulum", undated; 1.
    - Dr. John Alexander, "Some Important Points in the Surgical Treatment of Toxic Goitre", undated; 2.
    - Dr. Clyde O. Anderson, "Petrified Uterine Mycoma", October 26, 1921; 3.
    - Dr. C. H. Aufhammer, "A Radium Review", undated; 4.
    - Dr. Moses H. Baker, "The Function of the Clinical Laboratory", November 28, 1921; 5.
    - Dr. Moses H. Baker, "Value of Direct Examination of Exudate from Throats of Diphtheria Suspects", April 26, 1921; 6.
    - Dr. J. J. Billings, "Aneurism of the Iliac Artery", undated; 7.
    - Dr. Bixler, "A Case of Spleenomegaly with Spleenectomy" (two copies), undated; 8.
    - Dr. L. C. Bixler, "Restrictions from Intravenous Infections of Arsphenamin", October 27, 1921; 9.
    - Dr. Russell H. Boggs, "The Treatment of Epithelioma by Radium", undated; 10.
    - Dr. William H. Cameron, "Curative Possibilities of Cancer", undated; 11.
    - Dr. Jos. C. Chail, The sympathetic and somatic nervous systems, undated; 12.
    - Dr. S. A. Chalfant, "Excessive and Prolonged Menstruation Associated with Admomactus Hyperplasia of the Endometrium" (two copies), undated; 13.
    - Dr. Benson A. Cohoe, "Supraneal Inaufficiency and Organotherapy", November 22, 1921; 14.
    - Dr. Benson A. Cohoe, "Tumors of the Hypophysis, November 28, 1922; 15.
    - Dr. G. H. Curry, "Complete Double Luxation of the Eye-Balls", undated; 16.
    - Dr. N. P. Davis, "Laceration of Transverse Colon by Adherent Omental Band", undated; 17.
    - Dr. B. M. Dickinson, "The Lingual Tonsil", undated; 18.
    - Dr. John B. Dixon, "Carcinoma of the Breast", undated; 19.
    - Dr. H. H. Donaldson, "A Case of Henoch's Purpura Complicated by Intestinal Obstruction", November 28, 1922; 20.
    - Dr. H. H. Donaldson, "Some Points in Abdominal Diagnosis", undated; 21.
    - Dr. C. W. W. Elkin, "Report ofthe case of Carcinoma of the Scapula", undated; 22.
    - Dr. Wade Elphinstone, "Nitrous Oxide Anaesthesia in Mastoid Operations", undated; 23.
    - Dr. Theodore Elterich, "Report of a Case of Sclerema of the New Born", undated; 24.
    - Dr. Robert M. Entwisle, "Injuries About the Shoulder Joint", December 13, 1921; 25.
    - Dr. James K. Everhart, "Report of a Case of Brain Abscess with Ocular Manifestations", January 9, 1923; 26.
    - Dr. Sydney K. [Fenollosa?], "Polycythemia", undated; 27.
    - Dr. H. C. Flood, "Pyloric Stenosis", January 24, 1922; 28.
    - Dr. H. C. Flood, "Congenital Obstruction of Bowel: Case Report", undated; 29.
    - Dr. E. M. Frost, "Diagnosis of Peptic Ulcer" (two copies), May 31, 1921; 30.
    - Dr. E. M. Frost, "Observations on the Effects of Opium Alkoloids Used in Pneumonia Complicating Influenza", March 23, 1920; 31.
    - Dr. J. P. Griffith, "Reconstruction of the Common Bile Duct", January 31, 1922; 32.
    - Dr. C. C. Hartenau, "The Blood Picture in Several Types of Anemia Before and After Speenectomy", undated; 33.
    - Dr. Samuel B. Haythorn and Dr. Edward B. Heckel, "Rhabdomyosarcoma of the Orbit with Secondary in the Lung", undated; 34.
    - Dr. Edward B. Heckel, "Non-Surgical Treatment of Malignant Epibulbar Neoplasma", undated; 35.
    - Dr. Henninger, "Treatment of Neurosyphilis", undated; 36.
    - Dr. W. B. Hetzel, "Thrombo-Angitis Obliterans", undated; 37.
    - Dr. A. Vernon Hicks, "Etiology and Prophylaxis of Pneumonia", undated; 38.
    - Dr. Clarence H. Ingram, "Diverticulum of the Esophagus: Report of a Case", undated; 39.
    - Dr. C. W. [Jennings?], Oral sepsis as a causal factor in ocular disease, undated; 40.
    - Dr. S. H. Johnson, "Heat Stroke", undated; 41.
  - Scientific papers, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Dr. J. L. Johnston, "Symposium on Influenza", undated; 1.
    - Dr. David D. Kennedy, "A Case of Type III Pneumonia Simulating Typhoid Fever", undated; 2.
    - Dr. G. R. Lacey, "A Disturbance of the Isohemagglutinins in the Blood of Three Fatal Cases of Bacteraemias", undated; 3.
    - Dr. J. A. Lichty, "Medical Treatment of Peptic Ulcer", undated; 4.
    - Dr. James A. Lindsay, "Surgical Treatment of Ludwig's Angina", April 29, 1924; 5.
    - "Etiology of Athero Sclerosis", undated; 6.
    - "Pittsburgh Medical Review - An Early Medical Publication", undated; 7.
    - Dr. Watson Warshall, "The Negative Tonsil", March 25, 1924; 8.
    - Dr. E. E. Mayer, "Heredity and Intelligence" (absract), undated; 9.
    - Dr. W. H. Mayer, "Present Status of Luminal Therapy", undated; 10.
    - Dr. C. B. McAboy, "The Medical Impact of the Common Cold", undated; 11.
    - Dr. J. McCurdy, "Oxygen with Carbon-Dioxide in Respiratory Depression and Anoxemic Disease", January 30, 1923; 12.
    - Dr. N. N. McFarland, "Medical use of Pituitary Extract", undated; 13.
    - Dr. W. B. McKenna, "Traumatic Asphyxia", undated; 14.
    - Dr. E. W. Meredith, "Surgical Treatment of Peptic Ulcer", undated; 15.
    - Dr. W. C. Meanor, "Orbital Cellulitis in Scarlet Fever", undated; 16.
    - Dr. DeWayne G. Richey, "Spontaneous Rips of Thoracic Aorta, with Aneurysm", April 22, 1924; 17.
    - Dr. J. W. Robinson, "Morbitity and Mortality of Anesthesia", January 22, 1924; 18.
    - Dr. Ralph V. Robinson" Treatment of Lucaemia Hodgkins and Lymphic Sarcoma", undated; 19.
    - Dr. Z. R. Scott, "Treatment of 'Summer Diarrhea' wiht Special Referenec to Dehydration", undated; 20.
    - Dr. T. T. Sheppard, "Pulmonary Embolism and Infarction", undated; 21.
    - Dr. Paul R. Sieber, "Strangulated Obturator Eernia Coexisting with a Strangulated Inguinal Hernia", undated; 22.
    - Dr. J. R. Simpson, "Paralysis of the Sixth Nerve Complicating [Olitis?] Media with Regard of [Cancer?]", undated; 23.
    - Dr. Stanley Smith, Case studies of cataracts, undated; 24.
    - Dr. R. R. Snowden, "The Clinical Symptoms of Functional Disturbance of the Kidneys", undated; 25.
    - Dr. R. R. Snowden, "Renal Glycosuria: Its Differential Diagnosis", undated; 26.
    - Dr. Chas. C. Stanton, "Furunculosis of the External Auditory Canal", undated; 27.
    - Dr. James O. Wallace, "Internal Derangement of the Knee Joint", undated; 28.
    - Dr. E. U. Weisser, "Ocular Disturbances Occuring During Pregnancy and Puerperium", undated; 29.
    - Dr. George Wright, [handwritten and largely illegibile], undated; 30.
    - Dr. E. W. Zur Horst, "Cardiospasm with Esophageal Dilatation", undated; 31.
    - "Ethylene-Oxygen Anaesthesia", undated; 32.
    - "Report of a Case of Milroy's Disease or Persistent Hereditary Oedema", undated; 33.
    - "Diverticulitis, Citing an Unusual Cause", undated; 34.
    - "The Treatment of Uremia", undated; 35.
    - Case studies of Appendicitis, undated; 36.
  - Scientific papers, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Dr. Clyde Anderson, "Primary Carcinoma of Appendix", April 24, 1923; 1.
    - Dr. C. H. Aufhammer, "Removal of Vesical Foreign Bodies: Two New Methods", undated; 2.
    - Dr. M. H. Baker, "Case of Amblyopia with Recovery Following Removal of Diseased Tooth", October 27, 1924; 3.
    - Dr. Moses H. Baker, "Case of Congenital Syphilis with Apparently Healthy Parents", undated; 4.
    - Dr. N. H. Bennett, "Pseudohermaphroditisinus [Masculinus?] Externus", undated; 5.
    - Dr. D. H. Boyd, "Chronic Ulcerative Colitis", undated; 6.
    - Dr. J. J. Buchanan, "The Life and Character of Dr. Charles Emmerling", December 11, 1923; 7.
    - Dr. B. Z. Cashman, Three case studies: Recurrent Tubal Pregnancy, Inversion of the Uterus of Seven Months Standing,and Foreign Body Stone in Common Bile Duct, undated; 8.
    - Dr. B. Z. Cashman, "Spinal Anaesthesia", undated; 9.
    - Dr. Nelson H. Clark, "Herpes Zoster, Acute Posterior Ganglionitis", undated; 10.
    - Dr. A. H. Colwell, "Cardiac Conditoins in Arteriosclerosis", November 24, 1923; 11.
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "Complications of Duodenal Ulcer", undated; 12.
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "Empyema with Report of Ten Case Histories", undated; 13.
    - Dr. Theodore Diller, "Myaesthenia Gravis (I)", undated; 14.
    - Dr. W. A. Dearth, "Report of Case of Unusual Blood Tumor of Thigh", undated; 15.
    - Dr. W. A. Dearth, "Report of a Case of Congenital Atrision of Ileum", undated; 16.
    - "Report of a Case [of] Hydronephorsis of Kidneys with a Common Pelvis", undated; 17.
    - Dr. Elliott B. Edie, "Hyperacidity", undated; 18.
    - Dr. C. J. Ellis, "Changes in the Alcoholic", undated; 19.
    - Dr. Wade Elphinstone, "Nitrous Oxide Anaesthesia", undated; 20.
    - "Report of a Case of Pertussus Accompanied by Meningitis", undated; 21.
    - Dr. James L. Gilmore, "The Management of the First Stage of Labor, where it is Prolonged Due to Cervical Resistance", undated; 22.
    - Dr. G. W. Grier, "X-Ray Diagnosis of Peptic Ulcer", May 8, 1923; 23.
    - Dr. C. C. Hartman, "Arterio-Sclerotic Kidney", undated; 24.
    - Dr. Samuel R. Haythorn, "Our Present Knowledge of the Etiological Factors in Epidemic Influenza", undated; 25.
    - Dr. Edward B. Heckel, "An Opening Address on the Occasion of the R. W. Stewart Memorial Lecture by Chevalier Jackson", undated; 26.
    - Dr. R. R. Huggins, "Anaesthesia: Factors Which Determine the Selectoin of Anaesthetic", undated; 27.
    - Dr. C. W. Jennings, "The Early Recognition of Glaucoma", undated; 28.
    - Dr. Samuel Harris Johnson, "Poison Ivy Dermatitis", undated; 29.
  - Scientific papers, 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Dr. John Alexander, "The Significance of Pneumo-Peritoneum with a Report of Two Cases in Which This Symptom Predominated", Dec 23, 1924; 1.
    - Dr. Theodore Baker, "The Mechanism of Micturition", March 31, 1925; 2.
    - Dr. Theodore Baker, "Non-Veneral (Metastic) Genital Infection", April 5, 1927; 3.
    - Dr. L. C. Bixler, "A Case of Addison's Disease", November 10, 1925; 4.
    - Dr. D. H. Boyd, "Diptheria Prevention", January 13, 1925; 5.
    - Dr. Cashman, Case study of ovarian cancer, January 6, 1925; 6.
    - Dr. Nelson Parke Davis, "Compound Pathologic Abdominal States", 1928; 7.
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "The Use of Oxygen in Tuberculosis of The Peritoneum and Pleura", December 8, 1925; 8.
    - Dr. N. N. Donaldson, "Acute Osteomyelitis", January 27, 1925; 9.
    - Dr. N. N. Donaldson, "Some Comments on Ulcer of the Duodenum with Perforation", undated; 10.
    - Dr. C. W. W. Elkins, "The Interpretation of the Comatose State", undated; 11.
    - Dr. J. K. Everhart, Two case studies of boys with hemorrhages and skin lesions, undated; 12.
    - Dr. J. K. Everhart, "Infant Feeding", January 13, 1925; 13.
    - Dr. W. J. Fetter, "Allergy and Infection in Hay Fever and Asthma", undated; 14.
    - Dr. Henry C. Flood, Case study of Dermatitis Gangraenosa Infantum, undated; 15.
    - Dr. S. M. Frost, "Sodium Salicylate in the Treatment of Rheumatic Fever, with Patricular Reference to Rectal Administration", November 24, 1925; 16.
    - Dr. G. H. Grier, "Is Radiation a Satisfactory Treatment for Sub-Sternal Thyroid?", January 27, [1925]; 17.
    - Dr. T. R. Kendrick, "Some Observations on the Use of Artificial Pneumothorax", undated; 18.
    - Dr. Joe A. Lindsay, Raynaud's Disease, December 9, 1924; 19.
    - Dr. T. McC. Mabon, "Myxedema, with Report of a Case", undated; 20.
    - Dr. W. W. G. Maclachlan, "Is Accuracy of Diagnosis an Asset in the Treatment of Peptic Ulcer?", November 3, 1925; 21.
    - Dr. C. Howard Marcy, "Specific Cures for Pulmonary Tuberculosis", undated; 22.
    - Dr. F. W. Mathewson, "Some Factors Concerning the Etiology of Heart Disease", January 6, 1925; 23.
    - Dr. W. W. McFarland, "Some Thyroid Observations on the School Child", undated; 24.
    - Dr. William C. Meanor, "Post Operative Treatment and Case of Cataract", undated; 25.
    - Dr. H. G. Schleiter, "Case Report: Auricular Flutter with High Pulse Rate", November 24, 1925; 26.
    - Dr. Paul R. Sieber, "Tumors of the Breast", undated; 27.
    - Dr. J. R. Simpson, "Preventoin of Disease in Children: Nose and Throat Conditions", undated; 28.
    - Dr. J. N. Stanton, "Results of 100 [illegible] Cases of Uterine Curettage", undated; 29.
    - Dr. E. A. Weiner, On Cataract Removal Operations, undated; 30.
    - Dr. J. H. Whitcraft, "Diff. Diag. of Typhoid Fever", January 4, 1925; 31.
    - Dr. G. J. Wright, "The Neurological Aspects of Head Injuries", December 9, 1924; 32.
    - "Coronary Artery Obstruction", undated; 33.
    - Dr. G.W. Grier, "Roentegen Diagnosis of Diseasr in the Nasal Accesory Sinuses", November 10, 1925; 34.
  - Scientific papers, 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "Acute Osteomyelitis", February 14, 1933; 1.
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "Hyperplastic Tuberculosis of the Ileum", undated; 2.
    - Dr. Nelson P. Davis, "Practical Facts About Acute Appendicitis", undated; 3.
    - Dr. Holland Hunter Donaldson, "Abnormalities of Rotation of the Mid Gut", October 22, 1935; 4.
    - Dr. Holland H. Donaldson, "Report of a Case of Embolectomy ofthe Aorta", undated; 5.
    - Dr. C. W. W. Elkin, "Some Questoins and Problems in Diabetes Mellitus", undated; 6.
    - Dr. J. R. Everhart, Pneumonia, December 10, 1929; 7.
    - Dr. Ellis M. Frost, "The Differential Diagnosis of Gout, Infectious Arthritis and Acute Rheumatic Fever", March 26, 1929; 8.
    - Dr. J. P. Griffith, "Gastro-Duodenal Ulcer", January 3, 1928; 9.
    - Dr. R. H. Harrison, "Tracheo-Esophageal Fistula Caused by Lues", undated; 10.
    - Dr. Lloyd W. Johnson, "Diagnosis, Symptoms and Treatment of Gas Bacillus Infection with Case Reports", undated; 11.
    - Dr. David R. Kennedy, "Demonstration of a Tooth Extracting Key", undated; 12.
    - Dr. F. G. Schleiter, "The Treatment of Hypertension", undated; 13.
    - Dr. J. R. Stanton, "Acute Pelvic Infection", undated; 14.
    - Dr. Frederick B. Utley, "Addison's Disease", undated; 15.
    - Dr. Frederick B. Utley, "An Evaluation of the Recent Treatments Offered for Peptic Ulcer", undated; 16.
    - "Acute Osteomyelitis with Report of Cases", undated; 17.
    - "The County Society", undated; 18.
    - "Diagnosis of Neuro-Retinitis and Choked Disc and Their Significance", January 27, 1931; 19.
    - "Differential Diagnoses Between Non-Opaque Foreign Bodies in the Bronchus and Bulbar Types of Anterior Poliomyelitis with Case Report", undated; 20.
    - "Visceral Syphilis", undated; 21.
- Photographs, 1905; XV.
  Photographs of Annual Banquets of the Academy. See also: Series 11: Committees.
  - Annual Banquet, January 1905 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Annual Banquet, December 1905 (Box 13, Folder 2)